Hey guys, I'm going to answer a
question. Can I eat these vegetables on
a ketogenic diet? Well, let's go ahead
and talk about this because there's a
lot of confusion. So, we're going to
talk about like the beets, the carrots,
the peas, the tomatoes, and I'm going to
throw in potato, corn, art, artichoke,
too, because they they're kind of fall
in that category. So, um if we look at
beets, beets are really high in
potassium. I'm talking like 442
milligrams per cup. So all of these are
based on one cup and then the carbs are
13 grams and the sugar is 9 g. So
between the carbs and the sugar, the
sugar is the most important thing to
look at because you want to keep the
sugar down really really really low. So
if something has a higher carbohydrate,
it might break down the sugar very very
slow if the fiber is high.
um versus high sugar. It breaks down
into sugar really, really fast,
regardless of how much fiber, but fiber
does buffer it. So, okay. So, the beet
has about 9 g of sugar. It's pretty
high. Protein is 2.2, but look at this.
Fiber is 3.8. So, it has a good amount
of fiber, which will tend to buffer
that. So, the question is, should you
eat beets? If you're trying to get in
ketosis, probably not a good idea.
However, um if you're happy with your
weight, um like myself, um go ahead and
start eating the beets because they have
a lot of good benefits for the liver,
for nutrition,
um good for detox of the gallbladder,
that type of thing. So, uh generally
though, if you're trying to get in
ketosis, probably not a good idea to eat
beets. Okay, the carrot, 195 milligrams
of potassium. Again, potassium is
necessary to help lower insulin, so we
want that very high. Look at this. six
gram of carbs. That's pretty low
compared to a beet. It's like half.
Sugars are 2.9
uh grams. So, that is very very low
compared to a beet. Uh protein, not a
lot of protein. Uh half the fiber. So, I
would say carrots would be okay to
consume on a ketogenic diet. I don't
think you're going to have a hard uh a
problem with that because of these two
are very very low. And plus, all I mean
does have some fiber. So, I wouldn't try
to avoid carrots. Okay. All right. The P
peas, snap peas or just regular peas.
milligrams of potassium. That's pretty
high. 21 grams of carbs is pretty high.
Eight grams of sugar. Pretty high. Look
how much protein. Eight grams of
protein. Wow. That's interesting. That's
You ever hear of pea protein before?
Well, that's why. Um, you don't hear of
carrot protein, do you? And then we got
seven grams of fiber. That's pretty
high. So, peas. I probably would stay
away from peas simply because of the
higher level of sugar. Okay. All right.
Tomatoes, 292 milligrams of potassium,
4.8 gram of carbs. That's That's pretty
low. That's actually lower than carrots.
3.2 gram of sugar. That's still pretty
low. I mean, it's like just a little bit
more than uh carrots. So tomatoes are
probably a better thing to consume so
far than any of these other things we
talked about. Okay. So it's kind of tied
with carrot, but tomato is pretty pretty
low. Uh and then we have 1.1 gram of
protein, 1.5 gram of fiber. Okay. Not as
much fiber as the pea, but still there's
a little bit of fiber in there. It's
kind of similar to a carrot. Okay. So I
would say okay, consume tomatoes on a
ketogenic diet. So, so far carrot and
tomato are okay, but not beet and no not
peas. Now, potato, 897
milligrams of potassium. That is a
tremendous amount. Um, and then we got
37 gram of carbs. That's a lot of carbs.
And then, but look at this. We got 1.7 g
of actual sugar. So, it's low, but we
know this type of starch does break down
into sugar um faster than we'd like it.
4.3 uh gram of protein is pretty high.
And look how much fiber, 4.7 g. So, um
potato, even though it has potassium,
this is the culprit right here. This 37
thing. So, that's the problem with this.
It's the It's way way higher than 4.8 in
tomato or six six carbs. Okay. But it is
low in sugar. So, um if you're trying to
um if you're a child, let's say your
kids are younger, uh this would be
potatoes would be good. I would do sweet
potatoes and yam, red potato. Make sure
they're organic. Um it's not a bad food,
but this may slow you down losing
weight. Okay. Now, corn, 476
milligrams of potassium. It's pretty
high. Um
123 grams of carbs. So, this is why we
do not want to consume corn in addition
to all the corn is GMO, so we don't want
to do that. And then 1 gram of sugar.
Okay. Well, that's good, but still it's
such a starch. 16 g. I was really
surprised that corn has 16 grams of
protein. I just find that hard to
believe, but that was what the sources
said. Uh I'm not sure what the fiber is,
but um I don't know. Corn protein. I
don't know. I don't know. That doesn't
make sense to me. Okay. Artichoke
milligrams of potassium. So it comes in
second place just behind potato. And
then we have carbs 269
gram. Oh my goodness. That is it beats
all the other vegetables for the amount
of carbs. So this is really high in
carbs per cup. And look at this. 14 gram
of sugar. Artichoke is the worst thing
you can eat on a ketogenic diet. Um,
don't eat it. Now, protein, three, uh,
three grams. Fiber is 2.4. Okay? So, I'm
going to recommend that you stick with
the carrot and tomato and probably not
do these other ones. Okay? All right.
Uh, thank you for watching. I'll see you
in the next video.